<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Catherine Blatter</title>
    <link>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Catherine Blatter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using purrr::map() to identify data</title>
      <link>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/11/28/using-purrrmap-to-identify-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/11/28/using-purrrmap-to-identify-data/</guid>
      <description>last edited: 2019-12-28
What happened? Recently I wanted to explore plotting R for the first time and discovered the ggswissmaps-package.
I’m new to the structure of geospatial data so I read the introductory vignette and followed the examples.
Examples from the ggswissmaps-package #install.packages(&amp;quot;ggswissmaps&amp;quot;) suppressPackageStartupMessages(library(ggswissmaps)) suppressPackageStartupMessages(library(tidyverse)) # Data frame with the coordinates of all swiss districts d &amp;lt;- shp_df[[&amp;quot;g1b15&amp;quot;]] # Look at the structure of the data frame glimpse(d) ## Observations: 19,502 ## Variables: 21 ## $ long &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 679207, 680062, 679981, 680365, 680281, 680479, 680717, … ## $ lat &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 245176, 244294, 244051, 243411, 241866, 241584, 240695, … ## $ order &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 1… ## $ hole &amp;lt;lgl&amp;gt; FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, FALSE, … ## $ piece &amp;lt;fct&amp;gt; 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1,… ## $ group &amp;lt;fct&amp;gt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing Datasets with Swiss/German specifics: umlaut</title>
      <link>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/05/15/importing-datasets-with-swiss-german-specifics-umlaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/05/15/importing-datasets-with-swiss-german-specifics-umlaut/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is part of the ongoing collection Data preparation series. It collects hints for preparation of data by some of the ongoing multi-center projcets at the Institute of Nursing Science.
Why is this needed?  Many ongoing projects at INS are multi-center studies combining both survey- and routinely collected data
 Most of them have data coming from at least two different language regions (German- and French-speaking, eventually Italian-speaking)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting PubMed metadata with RISmed directly into RStudio</title>
      <link>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/04/29/getting-pubmed-metadata-from-within-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/04/29/getting-pubmed-metadata-from-within-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>What is this post about? Introduction - what were the problems I faced? RISmed package How to use RISmed?  How could my thesis profit from the RISmed package?   What is this post about?  For my master’s thesis (stay tuned 😎) I came at a point where I was interested in having a closer look at publication meta data (e.g. publications per year)
 PubMed usually does provide this service when you execute your search, for some reason it failed for my query</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful hints for Endnote</title>
      <link>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/02/16/useful-hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cathblatter.rbind.io/blog/2019/02/16/useful-hints/</guid>
      <description>💡 A collection of hints for working with Endnote this is a working document primarily addressed at students from the Institute of Nursing Science at University of Basel and may change over time - feedback welcome
What is this document and why? Endnote is the citation manager proclaimed in many courses at the INS. Over the past years I’ve encountered a number of struggles personally or through my peers. This document lists the major problems I’ve seen and offers solutions that worked for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>